# Kelati Andemichael

Seattle, Washington, United States



kandemichael@icloud.com



linkedin.com/in/kandemichael

# **Summary**

My primary focus is building engaging and outstanding ecommerce storefronts for clients and helping them achieve their business goals in the most efficient way possible. I love building bespoke features to exceed client expectations.

With over three years in ecommerce, certified developer in multiple SaaS platforms, I have experience leading/managing front end development teams with an agile-first mindset.

I also have a background in multimedia production, and I'm open to opportunities where I can leverage my diverse technical and creative skillset.

www.kelati.dev

# **Experience**

#### Development Team Manager

Overdose.

Jan 2023 - Present (6 months)

- Led a team of front end developers, providing mentorship and guidance to foster their growth and development.
- Successfully integrated an agile sprint model into the software development lifecycle, improving team collaboration, efficiency, and the ability to deliver high-quality results.
- Consistently improved team performance and utilization rate on a month-to-month basis, optimizing resource allocation and maximizing productivity.
- Orchestrated the successful launch of 3 enterprise e-commerce websites, ensuring seamless user experiences, robust functionality, and achieving client satisfaction.
- Led a high-performing team in a BigCommerce hackathon, resulting in winning the honorable mention
- BigDesign award, recognizing innovative and impactful solutions.

#### SaaS Dev Lead

Overdose.

Mar 2022 - Jan 2023 (11 months)

- Distinguished as the BigCommerce and Shopify Technical Lead, driving the successful implementation of these platforms for client projects, ensuring optimal performance, scalability, and customization.
- Honored with the Values Award for Quarter 1, 2022, among a team of 50 individuals, acknowledged as someone who consistently integrates the company's core values (Innovation, Empathy, Grit, Authenticity, Balance) into every aspect of their work.
- Led a cross-functional team to successfully migrate a large-scale client's legacy e-commerce platform to a modern and scalable cloud-based solution, resulting in improved performance and enhanced customer experience.

• Successfully managed a cross-functional team of developers, designers, and QA professionals, fostering collaboration, synergy, and a positive work environment, resulting in improved team morale and productivity.

#### O. Web Developer

Overdose.

Nov 2019 - Mar 2022 (2 years 5 months)

Overdose acquired Mercutio in June of 2021. The experience listed below includes my experience at Mercutio (November 2019 - June 2021).

- Collaborated closely with the UX team to define functional requirements, aligned designs for platform conformity, estimated and triaged user stories for sprints, managed Git Flow, and provided DevOps support.
- Led frontend development on dynamic client-side solutions using HTML, CSS, and Javascript frontend libraries.
- Optimized user experience by translating wireframes and mockups into responsive, mobile-first, and interactive features and websites.
- Built accessible applications that conform to WCAG guidelines, ensuring inclusivity and usability for users with disabilities.
- Demonstrated proficiency in working with various e-commerce SaaS platforms and CMS, including BigCommerce, Shopify, Klaviyo, Contentful, and Shogun



#### Support Developer

Sinclair Broadcast Group

Jan 2018 - Nov 2019 (1 year 11 months)

Sinclair Digital - Web Operations

- Triage and troubleshoot issues for nearly 200 individual stations with individual websites and multiple apps each, as well as OTT applications
- Build frontend with HTML, CSS (Bootstrap), Vanilla JS, jQuery, WordPress
- Query multiple data sources Error logs, Splunk, Jira (JQL), SQL
- Troubleshoot live event broadcast stream issues Touchstream, VDMS, Grafana
- Analyze traffic patterns with Google Analytics

HTML, CSS (Bootstrap), Vanilla JS, jQuery, WordPress, Splunk, Jira (JQL), SQL, Touchstream, VDMS, Grafana, Google Analytics, Chrome Dev Tools



#### **Multimedia Producer**

Sinclair Broadcast Group Oct 2016 - Jan 2018 (1 year 4 months) DataSphere Technologies Inc.

- Managed all aspects of creative production for customers marketing package.
- Designed and produced media products: websites, video and banner ads.
- Tracked impression and click-through rates to report back to client
- · Handled multiple projects at once and delivering products within SLA

# Videographer/Video Editor

Freelance

Sep 2011 - Dec 2017 (6 years 4 months)

- Edited over 50 informative e-learning videos for Science-Trak app for B47 Studios https:// www.amazon.com/Science-Trak/dp/B07GX6RN96
- Video Editor / PA / Extra "Fresh Pair", Seattle International Film Festival 2014 for B47 Studios
- Assistant Director / Assistant Camera for Festung Media films "The Art Next Door", "Us, Without You", "The Wish Fish", "8 Years Later"
- Camera Operator / Utility for live event multi-camera broadcasts and productions ESPN, PAC12, WSU Beasley Coliseum, UW Video

SLR/ EFP /ENG Cameras; Go Pro Hero; Studio/Field Lighting and Audio; Adobe Premiere Pro; Adobe After Effects; Avid MC 6.5; Final Cut Pro 7

#### 🔤 Co-Owner & Manager

Sodo Pizza

Jun 2015 - Jun 2016 (1 year 1 month)

- Co-owned and operated pizza retail business and par-baked pizza wholesale business
- Responsible for day-to-day operations, including profit management, inventory management, crew hiring and training, scheduling, quality control of all foods.
- Researched and strategically generated new wholesale orders with local bars and breweries
- · Drove customer engagement with social media campaign

#### Education



#### Code Fellows

Certificate, Advanced Software Development in Full-Stack JavaScript 2017 - 2018

## Washington State University - Edward R. Murrow College of Communication

Bachelor's degree, Journalism & Media Production 2009 - 2013

#### **Licenses & Certifications**



Certified SAFe® 4 Scrum Master - Scaled Agile, Inc.

Issued Mar 2019 - Expires Mar 2020 26352109-7873



## 🚅 BigDesign - BigCommerce

Issued Oct 2021 - Expires Oct 2022 LP38

# Contentstack Catalysts - Certified Developer - Contentstack 8493-2709702

# **Skills**

Front-End Development • BigCommerce • Shopify Plus • Shopify • Team Management • E-Commerce • Agile Methodologies • Content Management Systems (CMS) • Technical Documentation • Communication